Put that away .
Well done .
Not as good as last time , but good . Colleen ...
- Don 't forget , those of you who haven 't completed your tally charts .
Moron .
Quiet !
- Anna Madden , out ! - But it wasn 't me .
- Out ! - Sharon took my exercise book .
- Liar ! - Out now or you 're on detention .
- But it was Sharon . - Out !
No .
- Right , I 'll see you after school .
And wait where I can see you .
Nigel , did I tell you to stand up ? No , so get back in your seat .
Now , we all know how many degress there are in a circle , don 't we Nigel .
Quit ! The next person to laugh joins her .
Right , we 're starting something new today . Another way of showing
basic statistics .
Pie charts .
Now a pie chart is just another way of showing information .
Take for example the information we took last week .
Now what was the most common number of letters in all your surnames ?
Seven .
About half of you have seven letters in your surnames . So ...
what portion of the pie do those people have ?
Half .
180-degree slice of the pie .
Now I 'm going to make up a different pie chart
with a different set of information .
How we spend our day .
I 'll do an example for you based on my average weekday
then I want you to make up a pie chart based on your average Saturday .
First , I write down my information .
What are the things I do ?
Getting dressed and undressed .
Eating .
Travelling .
School .
Meeting friends .
What ?
- I feel dizzy . - She 's lying !
- I want to go home . - She 's lying , Miss !
I 'm not ! - Well you don 't sound ill to me .
If you disturb us again you 're going straight to Mr. Murphy . Understand ?
But it 's my birthday .
Well you should have thought of that before .
Quiet .
And you can wipe that look off your face , Sharon Davis .
Where were we ?
Sleeping . Right .
I spend one hour dressing and undressing .
About two and a half hours eating .
About 8 hours at school .
She passed out .
- Is she gonna die ? - Trisham , go get matron .
Thanks .
Hi .
How are you feeling ?
- Terrible , mum . - That bad , eh ?
Worse .
- Oh , but I 'm sure it 's nothing serious . - I wish they hadn 't called you .
- I could have gone home by myself . - Don 't worry .
Things were so busy at work that it was really nice to get out of there .
Listen , this 'll cheer you up .
It came after you left . Guess who it 's from ?
- Dad . - Yeah .
Happy 11th birthday . Lots of love , Dad .
Well , that 's not all . There 's something very special fixed up for you .
- What ? - No , it 's a surprise .
Riding lessons ?
Yeah , some surprise .
Where 's Mogadishu ? - I think it 's a port on the east coast of Africa .
Well they spelled my name wrong . - Did they ?
Oh ... it 's just a mistake .
- Maybe I could send a reply . - That 's a nice idea .
- I wish dad was here . - So do I.
- When 's he coming back ? - Soon .
How are you feeling now ?
- No worse . When is the riding lesson ? - It was meant to be after school today .
Meant to be ?
Let 's see what Dr. Nicols says first .
Do we have to ? I 'm sure if I just lay down in front of the telly I 'll be OK .
Doctor first . No arguing , okay ?
Stop ! Stop it !
- I was pretending . - Pretending ?
Sharon Davis stole my book .
Then I pushed her off the chair and Miss Vanstone put me on detention .
I can 't be on detention on my birthday , can I ? So I faked it .
You faked it ?
So you 're not ill ?
- Where are we going ? - Back .
- I can 't go back . - Oh , you 're going back .
- I 'll look stupid . - Well you do already .
Stupid cow .
Just because it 's your birthday don 't think you can talk to me like that .
You should be pleased there 's nothing wrong with me .
You 're telling too many lies , Anna , and it is going to stop .
- What about my riding lesson ? - Oh , don 't ask .
We 'll see .
- What does that mean ? - It means we 'll see .
I hate you .
Karen .
Come here .
- I was wondering where you got to . - Shh ...
Got the afternoon off .
I 'm having a really miserable birthday .
- You been using the sunlamp again ? - No , my skin just tans very fast ...
naturally .
I don 't get brown ; I get sunstroke .
Last year I fell asleep in a deck chair on my dad 's oil rig ,
and when I woke up I was burnt to a frazzle .
- Why 's your mum so angry with you ? - ' Cause she 's a cow .
What was Gary 's party like then ?
Lots of snogging . Not much else I can remember , really .
- You had a nice time then ? - I suppose you could call it that .
First I was upstairs with Nigel , then on the sofa with Ronnie ...
then Vaughn Hancock , pissed out of his head , got me on the thick pile .
You 're lucky you haven 't started that yet .
What 's snogging like then ?
Well , like kissing a vacuum cleaner .
This looks a real skill place to play hide-and-seek .
- I 'm too old for that kind of thing . - Bet you 50p you can 't find me .
- A quid . - You 're on .
Close your eyes , count to 100 , and don 't peek .
1 , 2 , 3 , 4 ...
86 , 87 , 88 ...
99 , 100 . I 'm coming !
Is anybody there ?
Karen !
It 's her .
Anna .
Don 't ever do that to me again . Never ! What has got into you ?
Mum , I don 't feel very well .
Now open wide .
My throat hurts ... like I 've swallowed dust .
Gritty ... and it aches , but that 's all .
You sure that 's all ?
No fainting fits ? No dizziness ?
And this ache , is it just in your throat ?
You 've obviously had quite an eventful birthday .
- I suppose you could call it that . - Sorry to drag you out like this ...
but I was worried .
I don 't blame you .
Look , I 'm sure there 's nothing to worry about .
She should have a couple of days rest .
What I don 't understand is what happened in the tunnel ?
Anna .
What happened in the tunnel ?
Fell asleep and lost track of time . You know ... .
- That doesn 't sound like you . - I 'll have that throat swab analyzed .
And you 're obviously running quite a temperature .
- And I think a day or two in bed ... - When it goes down can I go riding ?
- You must rest for a couple of days . - I 'm not staying in bed .
Don 't .
Well , think of it this way : if you rest now you 'll get better
sooner . You rush around , who knows how long it might take .
How long exactly do I have to stay in bed ?
I 'll come and see you again at the end of the week .
- The end of the week ? - Count yourself lucky .
I 've got a patient a little bit older than you whose been in bed for a year .
I 'd rather die than that .
You and he would get on well .
No we wouldn 't : I hate boys .
- I 'll see you on Friday then . - Goodnight Sarah
Here Sarah , I 'll show you out .
Is there someone who can come and look after Anna whilst you 're at work ?
No .
- I 'll have to take some time off . - You okay ?
Yeah . I could do with a break , that 's all .
Tired ?
Yeah .
It 's always difficult when John 's away , and I just ...
I don 't know ... .
Too sad .
Is anybody there ?
Can I come in ?
I can 't hear you .
- I said go away . - No , you let me in , then I 'll go away .
- I can 't do that . - Why not ?
'Cause there aren 't any stairs .
- How did you get up there then ? - I don 't know . I 'm just here .
Can 't you tell someone else to let me in ? - There isn 't anyone else .
Look , just stop mucking around and let me in .
Go away , don 't you understand , it 's dangerous around here , dangerous .
It 's real .
There are stairs .
- You were wrong about the stairs . - Must have come since .
Since I drew them .
You shouldn 't be here .
I knew I should 've made you more cheerful .
I drew you , this house , the stairs , everything .
Come and have a look , come on .
I can 't walk .
Of course , I didn 't draw you any legs .
I 'm not a drawing !
I 'm sorry , I just drew someone at the window , that 's all .
It 's alright .
My name 's Mark , what 's yours ?
Mark !
Mum ?
And one , and two , and three ...
- Mum ? - What ?
- Mum ? - Go away please .
- What 's wrong mum ?
Nothing , I just don 't want you ruining this print .
- Feeling better ? - No , worse .
What photo are you doing ?
The one you took on the beach last summer .
I 'm having dreams mum , but they 're real , I know they are .
Dreams can 't be real sweetie .
It 's dad !
They might frighten you but they can never hurt you .
- How do you know ? - Because if they could they wouldn 't be dreams .
- No , leave it , I like the clouds dark . - Alright , darling .
Oh that 's too much .
Come on , we 're gonna get you to bed .
- No , i 'll be alright if I stay awake . - No , come on , come on right now .
On the other side of the hill is the sea .
It shines out for miles and miles and everyone can see it .
It looks like glandular fever .
I lied to you about the fainting , it 's happened several times .
I guessed you weren 't telling the truth .
That 's all though , you didn 't need to come .
- I 'm getting much better . - Your mother was right to call me .
- Is it bad ? - Well , it 'll knock you out for a few weeks .
Your pulse is right up .
So are these glands .
- What have you been upto in here ? - Nothing .
- When did you last faint . - After I saw you , yesterday .
I see .
Sarah ?
- You know this boy you see ? - Yes .
When 's he going to be able to get up ?
Well , he can get up , he just doesn 't want to most of the time , that 's all .
He 's getting better though ?
You 're really interested in my other patients Anna ?
- Doesn 't he want to get better ? - Well of course he does .
Then why doesn 't he get out of bed ?
As long as he gets enough books to read he 's content to stay in bed .
That 's terrible , I can 't stand staying in bed .
If you told me I could get up tomorrow i 'd be up .
Well it isn 't just a question of getting up , it 's just that ...
Exercise is too much bother and pain for Mark .
- Mark , can 't walk ? - No .
What wrong Anna ?
We 're just opposites me and him , aren 't we ?
He 's got to do exercise and doesn 't want to ...
and i 've got to stay in bed and I don 't want to .
It 's a pity you can 't mix us up a bit .
Well I dare say you two are each better off as you are .
I 'll have a word with Kate on my way out .
Bye Anna .
Now he 'll walk .
Mark !
Mark ?
Oh , no cones .
Hi .
Whoever left this should 've left some instructions .
It seems to be based on the Apple design , it 's a bit crude .
I 'll fix that tomorrow .
I suppose you 'll tell me you drew it , that would explain why it 's so mental .
You 've been moving things around .
My name 's Anna .
- I drew you walking but it went wrong . - I don 't undertstand you .
- You like reading don 't you ? - Yeah .
- Then you are Mark ? - Well i 'm not a drawing , I know that .
I 've got the same doctor as you , Dr Nichols .
Not me .
- I mean ... when you 're not here . - Look , i 'm always here .
- They left me here . - Who left you here ?
It 's great , isn 't it ?
Do you want some fruit ? It 's really good for you .
Ok .
Behind you !
Very funny .
Very funny , I could 've broken my leg , you 're so stupid .
There was this boy ...
about my age ...
he had a bike , a blue one ...
it was in perfect nick .
Although he loved this bike , he couldn 't ride it .
He 'd just watch it every day and having it there made all the difference .
But one day he 'd ride it and that was all that ever mattered to him .
Why are you here Mark ?
I did something wrong , I expect that 's why you 're here too .
- I haven 't done anything wrong . - Oh I bet !
But I haven 't done anything wrong .
Maybe all this stuff 's here for you and you 're to stay here like me .
No chance , this is a dream .
That 's what I thought .
Do you think whoever brought you here will come back again ?
I hope not .
If my dad was here he could carry you ...
and you could run away with us , then you 'd be safe .
And you wouldn 't be afraid any more .
He looks like a madman .
Hello darling .
- What 's that ? - A radio .
- It doesn 't look like a radio , it 's too big . - It 's a radio .
Who 's that ?
That 's dad , that 's good .
I think he looks drunk , I hate it when he 's drunk .
He stopped drinking years ago .
He was drunk when I took that picture .
- Why don 't you have your soup . - He was , wasn 't he ?
Let me see .
Well , a bit , maybe .
You could rub it out and try again .
- I can 't . - It 's almost right , it 's just ...
His head 's a bit too big and he looks sort of angry .
What is it ?
Why don 't you go back to work , I don 't like you hanging around here .
- I 'll be alright . - Listen , it 's good , it 's really good .
- It 's total rubbish ! - It 's only a drawing Anna , come on .
That 's right , it 's only a drawing .
I think it 's good , I really do .
It 's just that i 'm having those dreams again ...
and i 'm frightened dad 's going to come into those dreams looking like that .
Listen , if dad came into your dreams that would be nice .
And no drawing is going to make any difference .
- Have I done anything wrong ? - Do you ever do anything right ?
I must 've done something really bad .
It 's nothing you 've done , that 's silly , don 't think that .
- Then why don 't you believe me ? - Believe what ?
That my dreams are frightening me .
- I do believe you . - No you don 't .
Listen ...
I know it 's hard for you with dad away all the time but ...
It 's hard for me too , we 've got to try to get on better .
- Will you promise me something ? - What ?
You 've got to be honest with me about when you pass out and when you ...
see things that maybe I don 't see , you understand ?
It 's really important Anna , you have to promise .
I always tell you the truth .
A nice hot bath and then to bed .
Mum !
- I don 't feel well . - I know , I know , you try and get some sleep , ok ?
- My head hurts . - I know but I have to dry your hair .
There , just a bit more .
Ok .
- Will you set my alarm for me ? - Why , are you going somewhere special tomorrow ?
- Set it for 7 . - Ok .
I 'll just get your teddy .
Stay with me until I get to sleep , I don 't wanna be on my own .
Sure .
I 'll just be a second , I just have to get something from my room .
No dreams .
- That was quick . - I 'm late .
Is something the matter ?
I 'm very busy this morning , I should be at the hospital .
Well perhaps I should 've got worse yesterday .
- Is anything wrong ? - No .
- You 're miserable today . - Well even doctors get miserable sometimes Anna .
- Is it something I did ? - Don 't think so .
- Bye . - Bye .
I 've given you some mild sleeping pills ...
keep a very close eye on her temperature ...
and let me know immediately if she seems delirious .
It 's not very likely , she seems stable now .
Sarah , are you sure you 're alright , you look worried .
It 's just a young boy I thought was ok had a relapse yesterday .
What 's wrong with him ?
He has muscular dystrophy , he 's got a chest infection .
- Oh no . - It 's dangerous .
Anna , what are you doing ?
Mum , last night you cleared up my bedroom ...
I threw something away , where 's the rubbish ?
I 've got to find it .
I leave you alone for 5 minutes and you work yourself up into a frenzy .
But I threw something away and i 've got to find it .
- What is it . - A drawing .
- A drawing ? Can 't you do another one ? - No !
Alright , i 'll go and look , but only if you promise to take 2 of these pills .
Yeah !
- Yes , yes , just find it . - Ok , ok , here , stop it , stop , here , Anna !
God , well if it 's not there there 's nothing I can do , ok ?
- No that 's not ok . - Well , i 'll find it alright .
Anna !
Wait ! Don 't !
Anna ! Anna !
Come back ! Anna !
Wait ! Anna !
Wait !
Come on love , out of the way .
No , I have to find something , I threw it away by mistake .
- To bed now , come on ! - No !
You 're going to be sick , really sick unless you calm down .
You 've gotta help me find it mum , please .
Can you help ? - What type of bag was it ?
Black !
Ok boys , we 're looking for a black bag !
Please , let me check them .
Open them mum , open them .
- You missed one . - I 'm doing my best .
It could be any of these .
- Look , you 've lost the drawing Anna , just accept it . - No !
- That 's your lot . - You didn 't check that one .
If we checked every one we 'd be here all day .
It 's no good Anna , stop it now .
There !
You 're going to be alright now darling , you must sleep .
Mark ?
Fooled you !
Your face .
Sorry Anna .
- How you feeling ? - Fine .
You did all this then , eh ?
I don 't understand you .
Mark , do you remember anything about the real world ?
But this is the real world .
I suppose so .
When i 'm not here I know where I am ... and you 're there too .
- What 's wrong with me ? - You 're in hospital .
I wish you weren 't , sorry .
Well you 're right about one thing ... I am ill .
I 'm tired , like i 've just run a marathon but all the time .
And the big joke is I have to crawl to move from this lump of wood .
- That must be really uncomfortable . - And cold .
Instead of making a mess out of this place ... why don 't you help me ?
I think I should wake up now .
- I can 't wake up . - I told you so .
- They 've come for us . - Who ?
- It 's dad ! - No , don 't let him in .
- Rubbish , i 'll go and fetch him . - No !
Dad !
Dad , come in , it 's getting dark .
- Anna , is that you ? - Yes .
I 'm blind !
No locks .
Anna , he 's moving , he 's got a hammer .
- Anna ! - Go away .
Anna .
Are you ok ?
Let me in Anna .
- Behind the hills is a sea , we have to go there . - You go .
- Listen , we can ride the bike . - How can I ride a bike , be realistic .
You ride and i 'll push .
- You 're mad . - Anna !
Please Mark , you have to try .
Anna , i 'm not going away so you might aswell let me in .
Let me in Anna ! Open this door now !
- You 'll never get me up on this . - Try .
Anna .
- Don 't leave me . - Of course I won 't .
- Don 't leave me . - Of course I won 't leave you .
- I 'm scared . - Don 't be scared .
There .
You 've had a really bad fever darling but I think this is the worst of it .
When you 're better we 'll go to the seaside .
You like the sea .
We 'll go there , all 3 of us , and we 'll have a big , long rest , ok .
To the sea , to the sea , to the beautiful sea .
Let me see , let me see it .
You 're temperature 's going down , it 's normal , you 're getting better .
- Don 't . - What .
- Who are you ? - Anna ?
I don 't talk to strangers , go away .
- Go away . - It 's mummy , you 're alright now .
Go away !
Anna !
What are you doing ? Darling ?
Anna ! Look at me , look at me !
Anna , please , don 't !
Anna !
Mark ?
He must 've taken him .
Anna ?
You 're going to be alright .
Just stay where you are .
Daddy 's here .
Anna !
Alright ...
if you want to play games ...
One , two , three ...
four , five , six ...
seven , eight , twelve ,
thirteen , fourteen , fifteen ...
It 's you he 's after not me , you should 've never come back .
I thought that he 'd taken you .
Listen. it won 't take him long to find us ...
You 've gotta wake up and change your stupid drawing , get rid of him .
I 've tried .
No , rip him out of the paper , it 's the only way .
- I drew a lighthouse , we can go there then we 'll be safe . - Ok .
Look , just wake up , we 're not going to get anywhere with him around .
I can 't .
- Wake up ! - I can 't .
Thirty-one , thirty-two , thirty-three ...
Thirty-four , thirty-five , thirty-six ...
I 've got an idea .
Lie down like you 're in bed ... do it !
Reach out to where the drawing is .
Pick up the drawing Anna .
Careful !
- Dad 's on the left , by the rocks . - Put your finger on him .
Eighty-seven , eighty-eight , eighty-nine ...
Now rip him out !
Ninety-nine , one hundred .
I 'm coming .
Run Anna , leave me .
Anna !
Mark , Mark !
Mark !
Get off me !
Who are you ?
- What is your name ? - Please , dad , please .
Do you know me ?
Do you recognise me ?
The sea .
Anna ?
- Anna . - It 's alright love , it 's just the tube .
There 's a brave girl .
You 'll be alright , you 'll be alright .
Anna ?
It hurts when I breathe .
That 's just your ribs , they 're a bit bruised .
The ambulance man had to give you a heart massage .
- He saved your life . - I know but it still hurts .
You 'll be out of here in a few days .
I 've been here long enough .
How 's Mark ?
- How 's Mark ? - He 's ok .
Don 't lie to me .
We sent him home , he 'll be more comfortable there .
He 's dying isn 't he ?
- They 've stopped . - What 's stopped .
My dreams .
If I tell you something , will you keep it a secret ?
- I know Mark , I know him from my dreams . - Anna ...
I drew a house on paper , Mark 's there too .
It was me who made Mark ill and me who helped him get better again .
Then we had to escape and we did but now I can 't even dream .
You have to believe me .
When you 're ill the mind plays funny tricks .
It 's not a trick ... Mark 's eyes are blue ...
His left leg is stronger than his right ...
He 's got a bicycle , a blue one , he just looks at it .
- How do you know all this ? - It 's true isn 't it ?
You have to get me my pencils and drawings , you have to .
- But ... - Just do it !
And as soon as you 're better ...
I 'm going to take us all down to Devon for a little holiday .
Hey , are you listening to me ?
Look at me darling .
That 's better , I was beginning to think I was invisible .
You don 't have to be invisible to disappear , dad .
Anna , you said you wanted to go to the seaside , no ?
Sounds wonderful mum .
Hey and don 't forget your riding lessons .
I 've taken time off , we can go together if you like .
And then you 'll go away again .
I don 't know what you want these for but here they are .
She shouldn 't have told you , I told Sarah to keep it a secret .
- Can I see ? - No .
I wouldn 't want to live if he died .
Now if there 's anything we need we 'll be alright .
Mark , Mark .
Anna .
Wait there .
How 's that then eh ?
I thought you weren 't ever coming back .
Come on , there 's lots to show you ...
You 've really kitted out the place good this time .
- Hey , what 's the matter ? - Nothing , just pleased to see you .
Come on , let 's walk along the cliffs .
Here , I want to show you something .
- Can you do rollovers ? - Yeah .
You haven 't done them properly until you 've done them here , my way .
What do you mean " your way " ?
Sit in front of me .
Keep your head well in and imagine you 're half of a wheel .
Now pull me .
Again !
How am I getting on in your world ?
You 're recovering but not as fast as here .
- So i 'm different here ? - Don 't know .
I don 't care what happens to me there , as long as I can be here with you .
You see , your world doesn 't matter any more , we can live here .
Have you ever kissed anyone ?
Me neither .
Is this snogging ?
I 've walked as far as I can along these cliffs but there 's no way down .
- We should draw a ladder then . - There 's not one long enough ...
And even if there was I wouldn 't go down there , would you ?
I know i 'm getting better but that 's just stupidity .
- You suggest something then ? - Helicopter ?
- I don 't think I can draw that . - I can .
I brought it with me this time . You draw the helicopter .
- Are you sure ? - Positive .
- Do you think it 'll work for me ? - Don 't know .
- Where are you going ? - I 'm going back to draw .
Wait .
You can 't go yet .
Well you wait down here and keep a look out for it .
I can see better from up there .
To be honest i 'd rather draw by myself , I don 't like people watching me .
- And I never saw you draw did I ? - I suppose not .
- You wait down here then . - Ok .
Don 't go without me .
Please don 't go without me .
I 've got some good news ...
They 've given me a job at head office so I don 't have to go away anymore .
That 's good isn 't it ?
We can all be together like a proper family .
Things aren 't the same between you and me since I got back , are they ?
I missed you when I was away but now I feel as if i 'm missing you even more .
I 'm worried .
- I went to see your doctor . - Why ?
Mum said you were having bad dreams about me , is that true ?
Do you want to see someone about the dreams ?
- I don 't have them anymore . - Maybe because i 'm back .
No , it 's nothing to do with you .
What did Dr Nichols say ?
She said you knew a patient of hers who died .
What 's the matter ?
Mark 's dead .
Didn 't you know ?
- I 'm sorry . - No , don 't be sorry ...
I knew , it 's just when I last saw him I sort of hoped he 'd get better .
Was he a close friend ?
- Dr Nichols didn 't tell me the whole story . - Obviously .
Mark would hate anybody being sorry .
Come on Anna .
Did you seen those boats there ?
- Good morning . - Good morning , Mr Madden .
Hello , is everything ok ?
That 's good .
After lunch we 'll go for a walk down to the front .
- Here . - Thanks .
Don 't lose it .
Dad .
I 'm sorry .
- What on earth for ? - Being so miserable .
Don 't be stupid .
It was the illness , when I was ill I thought I saw funny things .
I want to go to the pier ... to get Karen some rock .
- Well we 'll go after we 've eaten . - Good .
- Shall I open your curtains . - Whatever you like .
Be careful you don 't get sunstroke .
Mark , i 'm back .
Mark .
Mark , let me in .
Let me in .
I don 't want to go without you but the helicopter 's been hovering all day .
I think i 'm meant to go .
Wait for me here , i 'll come back for you , love Mark .
Mark , Mark , Mark !
Anna !
Move back from the edge , it 's dangerous .
- I can 't reach .
Move back from the edge Anna , it 's dangerous .
- Anna , move away ! - I can 't reach .
Mark , I can 't reach , don 't leave me .
- Anna , it 's dangerous . - I can 't reach .
- Move away from the edge . - Don 't leave me .
- Bye Anna . - No !
He 's alright now mum , I know he is .